# 大家好 這是我弟他們買的衣服哦
Hi everyone! These are the clothes that our brothers bought,
# 給狗狗它們穿上
for the puppies.
# 天氣冷啦 穿衣服啦
Put on more clothes! It's getting cold.
# 小狗
Puppies!
# 笑它衣服的樣子
I'm laughing at their clothes.
# 誒呦 還有個帥字哦 (註︰我不想先放拼音再放解譯，會影響雅興，就如電影字幕一樣，改些少意思吧)
Ayo! This word means "handsome".
# 你好帥哦
You're so handsome!
# 你看 一個帥字
Look! This word means "handsome".
# 它們在幹架
They're having a fight.
# 你看 就這幾條 這個胖一點的不用穿衣服
Look! The clothes are just for these puppies. This puppy is fatter and it doesn't need any clothes.
# 它的身體健康的很
It has an exceptionally healthy body.
# 啊 你看 吃得好飽啊
Ah! Look! It has eaten a lot.
# 給你看下你肚子 (註︰就是...給攝影小哥看?? XD)
Let him have a look at your belly!
# 大不大
Is it big?
# 它吃飽啦
It's full now.
# 最會吃
It's the biggest eater.
# 哦
Oh!
# 胖子
Chubby!
# 小胖子
Little chubby!
Liiiiiitle chuuuuubie!
# 嗯 看一下它
Um! Look at this one.
# 這個很乖 你看 這兩個黑狗
This is a good puppy. Look at these two black puppies.
# 天氣冷 它們就睡在這裡看
It's cold. They're all sleeping here, to look,
# 看家護院
to look after our home and guard our place.
# 所以給它們買了套衣服給它們穿
That's why we've bought them the clothes.
# 兩個小 小黑狗
Two pup... black puppies.
# 暖不暖和
Is it warm?
# 舔我
It licks me!
# 看你 嚇我一大跳
You see? You scared me!
# 給你曬曬大陽啊
Let you have a sunbath.
# 不許動
Don't move!
I say don't move!
# 叫你不要動就不要動啊
Don't move when I ask you not to move!
# 給你聽到沒有
Are you listening?
# 手給我 快點
Give me your hand! Be quick!
# 那個手也給我 這個手也給我 (註︰那個還是這個？)
Give me that hand too! Give me this hand too!
# 這個手也給我 快點
Give me this hand! Be quick!
# 快點給我
Give me your hand now!
# 不給我是不是 不給我 我自己抻[SIC]手來拉你 (註︰這裡我不再重覆「不給我」，英文這樣說不點怪)
You're not giving, are you? Then I pull your hand.
# 不可以起來
Don't get up!
# 這小狗都長那麼大啦 現在都三四斤啦
This puppy is getting that big now. It's almost two kilograms.
# 這個
It,
# 它嘴巴好大哦 你看這個又不像那個
it has a very big mouth. It doesn't look like that one.
# 這個又不像那個狗
It doesn't look like that puppy.
# 這個就像哈巴狗 這個又不像給巴狗
This one looks like a pug. And this one doesn't look like a pug.
# 來 躺下來給看一下 你看 (註︰我把最後一個「你看」放到下一行，避免連續出現兩個"look")
C'mon! Lie down and let me have a look!
# 他們兩個
Look! These two puppies,
# 哪裡像是親兄弟
how can they be brothers?
# 不像
No way!
# 這個嘴巴那麼大
Its mouth is so big.
# 這大嘴狗
This is big-mouthed puppy.
# 誒耶 這個
Eeeye! Its,
# 這個嘴巴又那麼小
and its mouth is so small.
# 小嘴狗
Small-mouthed puppy.
# 很乖呦 這個公的
It's a boy, a very good boy.
# 腳都受傷啦
Its leg is injured.
# 沒事 (註︰他經常說「沒事」，我不知這是普通話的常用語還是村霸的口頭禪)
But it's fine.
# 就這樣
Stay here!
# 它老是 很調皮 它
It's always so naughty. It's a...
# 這也吃得你看 吃得好飽啊
It eats, look, it eats a lot!
# 是不是們我家伙很好的還是
Is it because you have very good food here, or?
# 天天都有
Everyday,
# 天天都有米糠拌飯吃哦
you have rice and bran everyday.
# 你們 你們就像竹鼠一樣 吃米糠伴飯了
You, you guys are like the bamboo rats, eating rice and bran everyday.
# 現在它的牙齒好尖啊
Its teeth are very sharp now.
# 你看 它們在吃玉米 玉米它們也吃的哦
Look! They're eating the corns. They eat corns too.
# 它們也是水果餅乾 (註︰這裡我用英式詞彙)
They eat fruits and biscuit too.
# 米糠伴飯它們都吃 甚麼都吃
They also eat rice and bran, and everything.